http://www.sigmachi.org/privacy-policy-3

Privacy Policy
Statement of Policy on Privacy Sigma Chi’s member privacy policy is provided to help members understand how the Fraternity protects their privacy. This policy provides you with an opportunity to make informed choices about the management of your personal information. Call Headquarters at (847) 869-3655 or visit SIGMACHI.ORG for more information. If you have already instructed us how to implement your choices under the Sigma Chi Privacy Policy, you do not need to contact us again. We will continue to honor the choices you have made. Policy on the Collection, Use and Sharing of Private InformationSigma Chi has one privacy policy for consumers that applies to all Sigma Chi entities operating from the Sigma Chi International Headquarters at 1714 Hinman Avenue, Evanston, Ill. This includes the Sigma Chi Fraternity, the Sigma Chi Corporation, the Sigma Chi Foundation, Constantine Capital Inc., the Risk Management Foundation, Sigma Chi Leadership Institute, Blue and Gold Travel Services of Illinois, and Constantine Housing Initiative. It is our belief that one privacy policy makes it easy to understand and convenient for our members to make informed choices about the management of their personal information. Information covered by this policyOur policy applies to all personally identifiable information about you that is obtained by Sigma Chi in connection with your member records (personal information). Our policy will continue to cover information we may collect about you during the course of your membership in Sigma Chi. How we collect personal informationSigma Chi relies upon many sources of information to understand and meet your needs. We collect personal information about you from: Pledgeship application and membership records submitted by you or on your behalfOther ways when you communicate with us in person, over the phone, through the mail or through our Web siteChapter, undergraduate and alumni submissions;Governmental reporting agencies like the National Change of Address and U.S. Mail Federal agenciesInformation-sharing relationships that we establish with your institution of higher educationInformation provided to our vendors who respond to us to keep our information as correct as possibleWeb browsers, when you visit our Web site and your browser interacts with usOther sources in connection with providing you a product or service How we keep information secureInformation security is one of our highest priorities. This priority is emphasized by our Sigma Chi Fraternity Governing Laws, specifically prohibition on solicitation, this Privacy Policy, and the contracts and agreements that we sign with external vendors, suppliers and licensees. We limit access to personal information about you to those employees who need to know that information to provide services to you. Employees who violate our policies and procedures regarding privacy are subject to disciplinary action; our vendors, suppliers and licensees are also bound to uphold our procedures regarding privacy under the terms of our legal contracts with them. We safeguard information by regularly assessing security standards and procedures to protect against unauthorized access to personal information. Information sharing within Sigma Chi entities and your opportunity to opt outMembers often tell us that they prefer our current “integrated approach” to their membership relationship with Sigma Chi and our related entities. For this reason and others, we may share any of the personal information that we collect about you among the entities closely related and tied to Sigma Chi, including Sigma Chi Fraternity, Sigma Chi Corporation, Sigma Chi Foundation, Constantine Capital Inc., the Risk Management Foundation, Sigma Chi Leadership Institute, Blue and Gold Travel Services of Illinois, and Constantine Housing Initiative. If you prefer that we not share personal information about you with other entities within Sigma Chi as mentioned above, or with companies or entities outside Sigma Chi (except information described below under “Other Information Sharing”), you may opt out. That is, you may direct us not to share this information by calling Sigma Chi Headquarters at (847) 869-3655, or by sending your request via e-mail to update@sigmachi.org. Information sharing outside Sigma Chi entities and your opportunity to opt outIf you prefer that we not share personal information about you with companies and organizations outside Sigma Chi entities (except information described below under “Other Information Sharing”), you may opt out. That is, you may direct us not to share this information by calling Sigma Chi Headquarters at (847) 869-3655, or by sending your request via e-mail to update@sigmachi.org. If you choose to opt out of the sharing of personal information with companies and organizations outside Sigma Chi, we will not share any personal information about you. Choosing to opt out of this information sharing will limit opportunities for you to receive membership, product and service information that may be of interest to you. Other information sharingWe may also share personal information about you with companies or other organizations outside Sigma Chi as required by or permitted by law. For example, we may share personal information to: Protect against fraudRespond to a subpoenaService your membership records In addition, Sigma Chi may work with companies or organizations outside of Sigma Chi to provide services to Sigma Chi or its members, or to provide you with opportunities to buy products or services offered by either Sigma Chi or with companies or organizations contractually bound to Sigma Chi. Consequently, we may disclose any of the personal information that we have collected about you to: Other companies or organizations with whom we have licensing or marketing agreementsCompanies or entities that perform services, including marketing services, for us For your protection, we require that these companies or entities keep all personal information secure and confidential. Web linksWe are not responsible for the collection, use or security of information by companies, entities, organizations or chapters outside of Sigma Chi that may be linked to our Web sites. Members are encouraged to read the privacy policies of Web sites reached through the use of links from Sigma Chi Web sites. Children’s online information privacyWe do not knowingly collect, maintain or use personal information from our Web sites about children under the age of 13. If a child whom we know to be under age 13 sends personal information to us online, we will only use that information to respond directly to that child, notify parents, or seek parental consent. Sigma Chi entities providing this noticeThis policy is provided by Sigma Chi International Headquarters on behalf of: Sigma Chi Fraternity, Sigma Chi Corporation, Sigma Chi Foundation, Constantine Capital Inc., the Risk Management Foundation, Sigma Chi Leadership Institute, Blue and Gold Travel Services of Illinois, and Constantine Housing Initiative. Adopted by the Executive Committee in 2002.
SIGMA CHI
1714 Hinman Ave. Evanston, IL 60201
(847) 869-3655
headquarters@sigmachi.org
Quick Links
Donate
Sigma Chi Online
Chapter System
© 2020, Sigma Chi Fraternity
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish. Cookie settingsACCEPTPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are as essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
